<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: aliases | Hopeless Lomantic]]></title>
  <link href="http://dloman.github.io/blog/categories/aliases/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dloman.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-13T05:01:04-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://dloman.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Loman]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[update to cli script]]></title>
    <link href="http://dloman.github.io/blog/2014/07/13/update-to-cli-script/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-13T04:45:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dloman.github.io/blog/2014/07/13/update-to-cli-script</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>a long while back I wrote some little bash function which automatically create bash aliases for moving around commonly used areas in my file system. This worked awesome until one day I was working on a machine where i was not my normal username. I use a synced bash_alias file when I used the alias and moved to edit files in /home/dloman/Source/ and was not the dloman user things got very confusing when I tried to save my edits. Needless to say it took me awhile of thinking I was completly insane until I figured out what was happening. I edited the file with the sed command to replace the expanded <code>$HOME</code> path with the actual string <code>$HOME</code>. the command is as follows:</p>

<p><code>
function mark
{
  echo "alias $1='cd $(pwd)'" &gt;&gt; ~/Dropbox/Config/bash_aliases ;
  source ~/Dropbox/Config/bash_aliases
}
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alternative for quick cli filesystem navagation shortcutting]]></title>
    <link href="http://dloman.github.io/blog/2013/12/19/alternative-for-quick-cli-filesystem-navagation-shortcutting/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-19T22:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://dloman.github.io/blog/2013/12/19/alternative-for-quick-cli-filesystem-navagation-shortcutting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I saw this great <a href="http://jeroenjanssens.com/2013/08/16/quickly-navigate-your-filesystem-from-the-command-line.html"> blog post</a> about an easy way to create and remove shortcuts for commandline navagation to often used directories.
In the past I would often manually make bash aliases for commonly used directories, so I was psyched to automate this. I much prefer just typing the <code>DirName</code> instead of the <code>jump DirName</code> used in Jeroen&rsquo;s version, so I modified his commands with my own.
Here are the commands I came up with.</p>

<p><code>
function mark {
  echo "alias $1='cd $(pwd)'" &gt;&gt; ~/Dropbox/Config/bash_aliases ; source ~/Dropbox/Config/bash_aliases
}
function unmark {
  sed -e "/^alias $1='cd/d" -i ~/Dropbox/Config/bash_aliases ; source ~/Dropbox/Config/bash_aliases
}
function marks {
  cat ~/Dropbox/Config/bash_aliases | grep "='cd" | sed -e 's/alias //' -e "s/='cd / \=\&gt; /" -e "s/'$//" -e "/^  echo /d" -e "/&amp;&amp;/d" -e "/^  sed/d"
}
</code></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>This may not be the most elegant way of doing things (that sed command is fairly heinous) but it works great.</p>

<p>BTW keeping my bash_aliases file inside of dropbox is amazing&hellip;aliases and functions instantly appear on all my machines. It&rsquo;s rad.</p>

<p>P.S. originally I had the <code>unmark</code> command looking like this</p>

<p><code>
}
function unmark {
  sed -e "/^alias $1/d" -i ~/.bash_aliases ; source ~/.bash_aliases
}
</code></p>

<p>which seems like a only minor modification from the current version. This seemingly minor change of <code>alias $1</code> &ndash;> <code>alias $1='cd</code> looks like nothing, but one time I accidentally typed
<code>
$mark
</code>
which created the line <code>alias ='cd ~/WhereverIWasWhenIDidThis'</code> in my <code>~/Dropbox/Config/bash_aliases</code>
realising I just made a empty alias I immediatly tried removing the alias with
<code>
$unmark
</code>
which proceded to delete all aliases in my <code>~/Dropbox/Config/bash_aliases</code>!!!
That was interesting, thank goodness for dropbox backing things up (another reason to keep config files in dropbox).
Let me know what you think in the comments or hit me up on twitter.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
